A NETFLIX ORIGINAL SERIES
MADRID
77 DAYS UNTIL D-DAY
He's here.
Come on! Come on! We're 15 minutes late.
Come on!
-Just a second! Only the brows.
-Please. There's no time.
Hey!
On the stage.
For the last two and a half years,
many of you have called me a hero.
-Hero!
-So brave!
No, you are wrong, I am no hero.
I'm just an ordinary man
who was brave enough
to refuse to kneel before the terrorists.
That's why...
That's why I can be here today.
My dignity remains intact.
Meanwhile, those rats...
are still hiding in their holes.
GUNA YALA ISLANDS
Some people like those kidnappers.
-No way!
-Yes, believe me.
They find them funny.
And I keep wondering...
is a criminal funny?
-No!
Can a terrorist be considered a hero?
No!
How about the so-called
Professor Robin Hood?
-No!
-No! Helsinki...
the beast from the Balkans,
kept me suffering for 24 hrs
with an explosive to my chest.
Can he be anyone's idol?
-No!
I just hope...
he feels guilty for what he did,
every single minute of his pathetic life.
PAMPAS
ARGENTINA
I rushed the so-called Denver,
with just a a pair of blunt scissors.
He had an M16.
Suicidal?
Maybe, but as a result,
the first hostages could escape.
However, in exchange,
he took what I loved most.
Mónica Gaztambide.
-Forget her!
-My lover!
Yes, I've also made some mistakes.
I've also been one of the unfaithful.
One of the selfish and despicable.
As a result...
I lost everything.
Nowadays, every single morning,
I wake up and think
of whatever happened to my son.
JAVA
INDONESIA
Move over, you idiot!
Fuck you!
And your rotten bananas!
I love you!
Life...
Life is lost
if you don't make your mind up
and you let yourself go with the flow.
I was a hostage, but we have all
been hostages to something.
Yes!
To face that,
you need to make up your mind.
I make up my mind!
I face my problems! Repeat with me!
I face my problems!
I make up my mind! I face my problems!
GUNA YALA BEACH
PELICAN ISLAND
77 DAYS LEFT UNTIL D-DAY
My name is Tokyo.
Remember me?
The Caribbean.
For over two years,
my life has been a romantic movie.
We fish our own food.
Naked, wild...
But with some luxury.
And all of this is about to get fucked
by one simple thought
that's about to enter my head.
We've been here for more than two years.
Two years in paradise.
Paradise is wonderful
when your life is dull...
and full of traffic jams...
so you go there sometimes.
You need a change of scenery, don't you?
And I'm not a part of the plan...
am I?
We had a good run.
Rio...
I need to get out of here.
I need the hubbub.
I need people.
I need not to know where I'll be tomorrow.
I get it.
I'll also leave.
An adventure will do us both good.
It may be for a bit,
but I can't be sure.
Best to say it's forever.
In case we want to talk.
It's a satellite phone. I bought it
on the black market with Helsinki.
-Rio...
-It's unregistered.
Turn it on every three days, at 6:00 p.m.
If either of us needs to call,
turn it on for five minutes
then off again if there's no contact.
Okay?
My number is on the back.
011_8876__546E_32/47
I LOVE YOU
Come on...
It's going to get dark soon.
Rock on.
I can behave like a good girl
for a while.
But little by little,
my naughty side starts to come out
and eventually, it explodes.
And when I turn into a Sputnik,
three days fly by.
PANAMA
74 DAYS LEFT UNTIL D-DAY
They zip by so quickly that you forget
the only important thing you have to do.
SEARCHING SATELLITE
EUROPOL
THE HAGUE
Tokyo, pick up...
Shit, Tokyo, turn it on.
Shit!
Rio's position traveled from
the Guna Yala islands in the Caribbean,
to Europol in one second.
Then from Europol to the National
Intelligence Centre in 50 seconds.
Hello?
Less than a minute later,
Prieto was awake.
-Prieto.
-Colonel.
Europol has located Aníbal Cortés
on an island in Panama.
Contact the Panamanian police now!
Mine reached them even faster.
Target is out of town.
The phone was secure,
but the Libyan seller wasn't.
Eagle to Fox 1, we're taking off.
Hey, Rio.
That's her.
Hey, Tokyo.
Confirmed. It's Tokyo.
Police is on the way.
Sorry about the delay.
How are you?
I'm here. Three days watching time pass by
on this fucking island.
Police is in Cinta Costera.
Come on, come on!
I can't take it anymore.
I can't stand the Gunas' food.
For fuck's sake, I grew up eating
pizzas, burgers, fries, sausages...
That's what I want.
I don't want to be with these guys!
You can't even make them laugh!
Police is entering
the Torrillo neighbourhood.
Come on, come on!
I wanna party with you
and dance and get wasted
until our pupils look like a raccoon's.
That's what I want, Tokyo, fuck!
Even if it's just a date.
So you want a date?
Of course I want a date.
Then pick a city.
And I'll be there.
Rio de Janeiro.
-Shit!
-What?
-Patrol boats.
Patrol boats!
Run, Tokyo! They found us.
We are about to reach the plaza.
Alpha team, through the alley.
Back! Surround the building!
A COP IS NOT A FRIEND!
Alpha team through the passage!
Don't stop! Come on!
Eagle to Fox 1, we can't see the target.
Clear. Moving forward.
Cubeta, go through the Bodegón Alley,
in La Corrala del Muerto.
Come on! Come on!
Cubeta, she's inside the courtyard.
We are surrounding her.
I got you, bitch!
Bravo 2 in position.
Bravo 1 in position.
-Ready.
-Go, go!
-Lower your guns!
Easy. Lower your guns.
Negative. It's not her.
-Shit.
-Fuck.
Bitch.
That way!
Go, go, go!
Come on, go!
Guilty.
That's how I felt
while thinking about
every happy moment.
I had shared with Rio...
since we got free.
EDGE OF PORTUGAL'S TERRITORIAL WATERS
THREE YEARS LEFT UNTIL D-DAY
Ladies and gentlemen,
200 nautical miles.
We just made it into international waters.
There you go!
Hell yeah!
We're rich!
Rich!
Professor!
Come on!
Rich!
Finish the champagne.
We need new guidelines.
Professor...
Come on.
We have 10 million now.
Do you think we're going back to school?
We've managed to escape,
but now comes the most difficult part.
Staying alive.
Don't open them yet,
wait until you're on your own.
-What's this?
-Safe houses. Every couple has one.
So you and Helsinki
will stick together?
Of course.
Great.
You'll be under protection
and surveillance.
So, Interpol's reach will be very weak.
-Not now, Denver.
-I didn't do anything.
Open them when you're on your own.
I'm the only one who should know
your whereabouts at any given moment.
What are those numbers for?
Each number belongs to a continent.
A continent on which
you might find yourself in need of help.
Commit them to memory.
Now.
COLOMBIA
72 DAYS LEFT UNTIL D-DAY
These are phone numbers.
In an emergency, call the number
that corresponds with your location
to speak with your handler.
The handlers are sleeper cells
that will bring you to me
safely.
Hello?
My name is Tokyo,
and I'm looking for my handler.
Not joining them?
In a moment.
What about you?
What about me?
Where are you going?
I hope you won't ever need
to find out, Miss Tokyo.
But that day came.
THAILAND
62 DAYS UNTIL D-DAY
I imagine the same happens
in every paradise.
In the end, someone bites the apple
and everything goes to shit.
Let's go.
Go in. They'll come for you.
It took me 11 days to reach the temple
where my handler left me.
After an oil tanker, two cargo planes
and who knows how many buses...
Miss Tokyo.
...my guardian angel appeared.
Welcome to Thailand.
Hello.
I don't think I've ever been so happy
to see somebody.
Professor...
Have you heard from Rio?
Mom!
PALAWAN
62 DAYS LEFT UNTIL D-DAY
Mom! Mom, are you okay?
Are you okay?
Are you cold?
Let's get out of the water.
Come on.
Yes, yes...
What happened, Mom?
It's okay, darling. Grandma was just...
My mom was fully dressed
in the water again.
The water felt so good...
Raquel.
How did your trip go, darling?
Pack your bags.
What's going on?
Tokyo's here.
Raquel, Raquel...
Until we know for sure what's happened,
you must take your mother
and your daughter to Mindanao.
And even though this place isn't safe,
you're going to stay.
It's for the best.
Because you have to fix a problem
for Tokyo.
On your own.
If you are thinking of hiding me
so she won't see me,
you'd better think again.
-What's that bitch doing here?
-Calm down. She's one of us now.
Put it this way. I changed sides.
You know who changes sides during a war?
-Traitors.
-Tokyo...
-The lowest of the low.
-Tokyo!
You know what happens with those rats?
They can change sides once, twice,
a hundred million times.
-Tokyo, please...
-She'll betray you!
She'll betray you as she betrayed them.
-That won't happen.
-Why not?
How can you know? Tell me!
-I know.
-Really?
-And I'm absolutely sure.
-Sure?
Down in your pants?
If the Professor tells you I'm one of you,
then I'm one of you.
Is that clear?
Nice smack you delivered.
We're not going to get along like that,
Inspector
Lisbon.
My name is Lisbon.
Well, afterrthis touching reunion,
let's go have some tea.
Please.
-Hands up!
-Get down!
I told you to get down!
Hands behind your back!
Don't move!
How long ago was that?
Eleven days.
Where did you get the satellite phones?
When we split into two ships,
we were in port in Casablanca
for 24 hours.
He bought them on the black market.
From a Libyan.
In Casablanca...
They were unregistered.
Of course they were.
Not only that...
The vendor sold us out
for the reward money.
Professor...
Are you completely sure Rio's been caught?
He'd have rung his handler like you.
Don't you think?
But nothing's been published.
He was arrested 11 days ago.
It's the best news
the government can announce.
Why would they keep it secret?
It's a bombshell.
How long can they keep him hidden?
Seventy-two hours.
Where's he being held?
They're not torturing him, are they?
I don't know, Tokyo. I don't know.
Of course he's being tortured.
In any democratic country,
there's a backyard for playing dirty
in case things turn nasty.
And we've made things very nasty for them.
Well, you did.
They can't torture him.
It's the 21st century.
Sure they can.
At a height of 35,000 feet,
above any jurisdiction,
on the CIA flights or in Guantanamo.
Even Spain had terrorist commandoes.
Are you fucking kidding me, Tokyo?
Were you born yesterday?
Professor.
We need to get Rio out.
Are you listening?
We need to rescue Rio.
Did you buy any more phones?
Yes. Helsinki.
We have to gather everyone.
Professor!
Tell me you're going to save Rio.
How, Tokyo?
We don't even know what country,
prison or goddamn hole he is in.
We know nothing.
Nothing.
Professor!
I'm so happy to see you.
So happy.
-Miss Gaztambide.
-You can say "Mrs"! We got married!
Balinese rites,
an elephant and everything.
Tokyo!
Tokyo! Tokyo!
Do you want to come with me?
Professor!
Slow down, Helsinki!
Slow down, this is not funny!
Helsinki!
Asshole!
My dress!
What's up?
Nobody is going to hug me or what?
Let's toast in silence.
Don't wake the boy up.
Say it with an Argentinian accent.
Hey, boludo.
Listen to me, congratulations.
The worst Argentinian accent
I've ever heard. For real.
-Your house is so beautiful.
-It feels like heaven in here.
-Where's Rio?
-He knows.
Rio isn't coming.
He's been arrested.
When was that?
Seventeen days ago on a Caribbean island.
It hasn't made the papers.
He's in some shithole, being tortured.
How did they find him?
He used a satellite phone.
Was he in danger?
No.
There were rules.
No Europe.
No phones.
What the fuck are we doing here?
For safety reasons.
Safety reasons, what safety reasons?
Rio didn't know where we were.
Guys...
We must help him.
Let's see...
What the fuck are we doing here?
Do you really think
we're going to rescue Rio?
Yes, Denver.
That's exactly what I think.
Jesus Christ...
You made me cross the world
with a small baby to tell me that shit?
Are you smoking opium
in Asia, Professor?
Please, sit down.
This isn't a fucking video game.
You're not my boss.
Sit down.
You owe me your fucking life!
Do you understand that?
You owe me all this. That fucking backyard
and even that fucking sea
because you can't bring my dad back.
Got it?
Listen, I have a son.
I fucking swear I won't let him suffer
as much as I did.
Ask him yourself
if he wants his daddy to get riddled
with bullets.
Denver.
He's being plunged into a bathtub,
with a bag around his head.
-Do you understand?
-Sorry but that's his fucking problem.
That face...
you're looking at
is the same face
your dad was looking at
while you were trying
to dig the tunnel.
She didn't leave his side,
not for a second.
Tokyo was there.
Rio made a mistake.
But you also made some mistakes.
You dragged your dad to the rooftop.
You two could have been killed.
But the gang was there.
Helsinki, you took the car
to the scrapyard, but didn't crush it.
We fixed it.
The gang was there.
You stopped the machines late,
Nairobi.
And the police came in.
And you could escape through the tunnel
because Berlin...
stayed to hold them back.
He gave us the seconds we needed.
The gang was there.
The one not here now...
is Berlin.
Neither is Oslo.
Nor Moscow.
No way...
She's one of us.
I made a mistake.
I lost control.
But the gang was there.
Now Rio has made a mistake,
like we all have.
I can't ask you
to feel what I feel, but...
I feel truly responsible
that some... son of a bitch...
is giving him electric shocks
while he hangs from his ankles.
I'll go!
You're not going, Nairobi.
Because if you're going, I'm going too.
Here we go again.
How are we going to rescue Rio?
With a robbery. That's what we're good at.
A robbery? That's how we'll rescue him?
It will begin with...
a robbery.
But...
But we're really going to defy the system.
This time we won't be those guys
who kidnap people to make their own money.
We'll be the guys who take a stand.
The guys who say, "Enough is enough."
What they're doing to Rio
is a declaration of war.
And we are the resistance.
Right?
What are we going to rob?
The gold.
Gold?
Not just gold.
The gold.
The only gold that matters.
The national reserve of the Bank of Spain.
That's a big one, isn't it?
Never bigger.
And that idea just came to you now,
looking at the sunrise?
No, it's not my plan.
Your father's?
No. It's not my father's.
FLORENCE
5 YEARS LEFT UNTIL D-DAY
Andrés.
Little brother.
Welcome to Italy.
A country with art, class...
where people are stylishly dressed.
Unlike you.
You look like a traveling salesman.
Follow me.
I'm taking you to my humble abode.
I've got so much to tell you.
This is "the humble abode
in the country" you were going to rent?
You begin a search for a house
with two bathrooms and a garden,
and end up renovating a monastery.
I know how to break into the Royal Mint.
Through the door?
The back door. On the truck
with the with the spools of paper.
Andrés, there's people here.
Don't worry, we don't cross paths.
They're the perfect neighbors.
-They're monks!
-Cistercians.
They live in one wing,
we're in the other.
Besides, they swore a vow of silence.
They swore to remain silent.
Not before a gun, or a judge,
but before God Almighty.
Much more interesting, isn't it?
And...
what did you tell them?
That I'm an intellectual
in need of austerity and solitude
so I can write a treaty
on theological philosophy.
Did they believe you?
I also paid for the refurbishment
so they didn't have to turn this beauty
into a hotel.
They don't need anything else.
They adore me.
Sometimes I even sing
Gregorian chants with them.
Watch your head.
Andrés, do you sleep in a cell?
I intended to. But I fell in love...
with this chapel.
It's wonderful, isn't it?
Sergio, my dearest friend.
Long time no see. Come here.
What's all this?
Do you remember the plan to rob the gold
from the Bank of Spain?
It's amazing. We can obtain
up to 90 tonnes of gold from there.
We found the answer.
And I think you'll love it.
It's the most intelligent piece of civil
engineering since the Panama Canal...
Wait a minute.
I've told you a million times:
you may get the gold, but, Andrés,
there's no way
you'll leave the Bank of Spain alive.
Those are just insignificant details.
The gold comes first.
We'll deal with
the people after, okay?
-What do you mean "insignificant details"?
-Let's think about it later.
Don't you think
I look a bit different?
-Well...
-I have to tell you about a woman.
Look at this...
little cutie.
Let me introduce you to Tatiana.
Yes, she's really pretty.
She's madly in love.
A goddess.
The Professor never imagined
that one day
he would have to make
that suicidal plan his own.
WELCOME
BACK
Okay. Most of you know the rules,
but since there are some new faces,
we'd better review them.
First of all, no personal relationships.
Well, that rule's been...
The second rule is:
no first or last names.
Professor.
Let's get down to business. How are we
going to break into the Bank of Spain?
By making a racket.
MADRID
D-DAY
Nowadays,
wars start with bombings.
Ours did as well.
That day, 140 million euros
poured out over Madrid.
That was our way of saying...
"We're back."